<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Haris Karagiannakis</title><link>https://ckarag.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://ckarag.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ckarag.github.io/media/icon_hu994178d56f0916003447791abc6df026_39081_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://ckarag.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>US Inflation Dynamics</title><link>https://ckarag.github.io/project/ann_bab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckarag.github.io/project/ann_bab/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this project I employed neural networks to explore whether I can increase the realized portfolio return obtained from the long-component of the academically motivated low-beta factor strategy in the US equities space. The network was set to forecast the next-day trade direction signal of several pre-selected stocks &amp;ndash;the pool of low-beta stocks. The idea of employing an ANN signal generation model, was to add a second layer of improvement on the already over-performing stocks as implied by the market anomaly and the underlying factor strategy. The network successfully detects buy signals allowing to ’hand-pick’ several stocks from an already well-performing pool of stocks. My ANN-based investment strategy systematically achieves portfolio gains (as captured by increases in risk-adjusted returns) over the benchmarks. In particularly, over the period 2009-2017, my algorithmic strategy on average increases the Sharpe ratios by 65% and triples the FF5-alphas compared to the standard overperforming low-beta factor decile portfolios (P1-P3). My best performing ANN portfolio (comprised of the 330 lowest-beta US stocks, before ‘hand-picked’ by the network) achieves a 126% increase, resulting a Sharpe ratio of 5, translating to a ratio of 7.7 relative to the Sharpe of the S&amp;amp;P500 with dividends reinvested.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>US Inflation Dynamics</title><link>https://ckarag.github.io/project/inflationdyn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckarag.github.io/project/inflationdyn/</guid><description>&lt;p>Visualizing the change in inflation dynamics as captured by LASSO using a large macro dataset (FRED-MD).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Productivity in Cyprus</title><link>https://ckarag.github.io/project/productivitycy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ckarag.github.io/project/productivitycy/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>